saikishan sigh thakur

Full stack Dev

130 descanso dr, CA 95134, San Jose, California US

Sai.k.tech@gmail.com □ 8327860143

in Saikishan Singh Thakur

A Full stack developer with a 10 years of experience, played many hats, especially - A Dev, UI Manager, Architect and a Systems Engineer. Have been extensively working on many Technologies with primary focus on web - HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT; ¡Query, React, Angular, Backbone etc

SKILLS

Web Development Master	Backend Development Good	Tools & Scripting Good
html css sass less javascript reactjs angular jest figma photoshop node express mondodb firebase	node js python perl java c/c++ mondodb firebase firestore	aws azure sql postgress networking technologies - temip, nnm, ovpi shell scripting web hosting tools deployment tools

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack UI Dev Manager at L&T Technologies October 2018- October 2020

http://ltts.com

As a UI Manager working on many UI projects across L&T Services - clients; Cisco & GE

- Have lead many projects inside L&T internal and client facing
- Have developed many webapps using technologies like React, Angular and Vanilla JS
- Have worked with stake holders, Product Owners and Business Leaders to understand and improve Web apps
- Have brought in many best practices code reviews, PWAs, Mobile first dev
- Have introduced UI tech talks and News letters on Hybrid app development React and ReactNative being a primary essense
- Coached many small teams internally

UI Lead UI Architect at MicroInfo Inc January 2014- September 2018

http://microinfo.com

Worked as a Full stack dev and UI Manager to clients - GE, Walmart Labs and Cisco developing web applications

- Developed Web apps using Technologies like React, Angular and Many JS frameworks
- Wrote end to end testing and integrations tests
- Involved in many design discussions and product improvements latency management, scaling apps, migration etc
- Worked to create many reusable Components & Libraries
- Worked on Deployments Kubernetes & Docker
- Mentoring and learning new technologies

Systems Engineer at Hewlett Packard August 2008- December 2012

http://hp.com

Started Career fresh out of college. Have worked as an Systems Engineer

- Worked on PYthon code to develop the web services and Network Modules
- Developed Many web and desktop softwares across HP NNM, TeMIP, OVPI etc
- Worked on many Unix and Linux environments

Worked on design and developing web apps

EDUCATION

Masters of Computer Science Software Development at USF 2013 - 2014

Grade: 4.0

LANGUAGES

EnglishHindiTeluguExcellentNative speakerExcellent

INTERESTS

Reading Nutriton Indoor & Outdoor sports